Saving the world can be a trip.
The Mitchells vs. the Machines is a animation,
adventure, comedy film directed by Mike Rianda.
A quirky, dysfunctional family's road trip is upended when they find themselves in the middle
of the robot apocalypse and suddenly become humanity's unlikeliest last hope.
Katie / Dog Cop (voice), played by Abbi Jacobson.
Rick (voice), played by Danny McBride.
Linda (voice), played by Maya Rudolph.
Aaron / Furbies / Talking Dog / Wifi Enthusiast (voice), played by Mike Rianda.
Mark (voice), played by Eric André.
PAL (voice), played by Olivia Colman.
The Mitchells vs.
the Machines is a 2021 animated science fiction road comedy film directed
by Mike Rianda, who co-wrote the screenplay with Jeff Rowe.
Produced by Columbia Pictures and Sony Pictures Animation in association with Lord Miller Productions, and One Cool Films, the film stars the voices of Danny McBride, Abbi Jacobson, Maya Rudolph,
Rianda, Eric André, and Olivia Colman, with Fred Armisen, Beck Bennett, John Legend, Chrissy Teigen, Charlyne Yi, Blake Griffin, Conan O'Brien, and Doug the Pug in supporting roles.
The story follows the dysfunctional Mitchell family, who must
save Earth from a global uprising of robots.
Rianda conceived the film after completing work on the
animated series Gravity Falls in 2015.
The project was announced in May 2018.
To achieve a "hand-painted watercolor" style, technology was reused from the previous
Sony Picture Animation film, Spider-Man: Into the Spider-Verse (2018).
Lord and Miller's frequent collaborator Mark Mothersbaugh composed the score.
The Mitchells vs.
the Machines was planned for theatrical release by Sony
Pictures Releasing under the title Connected in 2020.
Due to the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on theaters, Sony sold
the distribution rights to Netflix outside of China.
Netflix retitled it to Rianda and Rowe's original title, and gave it a limited release in the
United States on April 23, 2021 before its streaming release a week later on April 30.
The film received acclaim for its animation, voice acting,
action sequences, themes, humor and visual effects.
It was nominated for Best Animated Feature at the 33rd Producers Guild of America Awards, the 75th British
Academy Film Awards & the 94th Academy Awards  and won the category at the 27th Critics Choice Awards.
It swept all the categories it was nominated for at the 49th Annie Awards, including Best Animated Feature, making it
the second film by Sony Pictures Animation to do so after Spider-Man: Into the Spider-Verse in 2019.
A sequel is in development.
The film explores themes of man vs machine, technology,
dysfunctional family, family relationships, family drama.
The tone is lighthearted.